The future
未來
The polar ice caps have melted
南北極冰水徹底融化
covering the Earth with water
地球被淹沒在海洋中
Those who survived have adapted...
倖存者逐漸建立一個新世界
to a new world.
"水世界"
Bad luck, English.
夠倒霉的 說英語吧
But the Slavers are producing a good grade of poxy these days.
最近那些販奴商生產出了一種效果很好的氧化劑
Cost you a handful of dirt... or maybe that wind chime.
跟你換一把泥土 或是那個風鈴
- What are you doin' here? - Just waiting.
- 你來這媟F嘛? - 等你唄
Take your hand off the sail.
你的臭手別碰船帆
Take it off!
手拿開
I've seen your boat before. Haven't seen you.
我之前見過你的船 卻沒見過你
Took it legal.
是合法的先占
Previous owner was dead on the tiller when I found it.
我發現這船的時候船主已經死了
You had another hour before I traded up again.
我高價轉賣之前你還有一個小時的時間考慮
Just improving my means.
賺得更多是我的宗旨
- Well, I owe you then. - No, thanks.
- 好吧 算我欠你個人情 - 謝啦 不用了
I got all the supplies I need. Just came from an atoll.
我的裝備已經補足了 我才從一個環礁基地出來
Eight days east, if you're interested.
你想去的話 向東航行八天
- Two drifters meet, something needs to be exchanged. - I know the code.
- 海行者碰面通常都要交換 - 我知道規矩
But I'll give you this one for free.
但是這次我就免費給你
Nothing's free in Waterworld.
在這片汪洋中絕不會有免費午餐的
Ha-ha. Yeah.
是啊
Smokers.
是掠海者
Just enough wind to get away clean.
風勢正好助我順利開溜
Forget the bag.
就別管那包東西了
It's not worth it. You'll never make it with your sails down.
那不值得你一搏 更何況你連帆都沒拉起來
What can I say?
祝你好運啦
- Joe, he's goin' for it. - What the hell?
- 喬 他要開溜 - 搞什麼鬼?
Never seen that before.
真是大開眼界啊
Here we go! Go! Drive! Drive!
快啟動 快啊 快踩油門
Faster! Faster! Whoo!
快點 再快點
Come on! He's gonna get it! He's gonna get it!
快點 要被他搶走了
- Pick her up! - Get it! Get it!
- 快逮他 - 上呀! 上呀!
Oh, no!
不 別
Inbound! Straight out from the gates.
有船接近 到門外了
English.
英文
Flag's down, drifter. We got enough traders.
已經收市了 海行者 今天已經不再交易了
Dirt.
泥土
Open the gates!
開門
Bones to berries.
化骨為漿
Veins to vine.
抽脈為藤
These tendons to trees. This blood to brine.
肢骨化為大樹 血漿變鹽水
Too old she was.
歲月奪走了她的生命
This woman does leave us
但她卻恩澤予我們
ecycled and enshrined in the presence of Him who leads us.
我們在上帝面前收下她的恩澤並銘記她
What is that?
那是什麼?
You know me?
你認識我嗎?
I know what you are.
我知道你是誰
Good. Then you know if you look for trouble while you're here,
很好 那你自然知道在這兒鬧事
you'll find more than you can handle.
只會讓你吃不完兜著走
You got two hours.
我給你兩個小時
I'll only need one.
我只需要一小時
He's comin' over here.
他走過來了
- Me. - You each get one...
- 給我 - 賞你們一人一個
if everything's here when I get back.
只要能在我回來前幫我看好船
Pure dirt.
純泥土
3.2 kilos.
3.2公斤
How'd you come by so much of it?
你從哪兒找來這麼多泥土?
Another atoll 30 horizons west of here.
從這兒向西差不多30個海平線遠的另一個環礁基地那兒
Where'd they get it?
那他們是在哪兒弄到的呢
- They didn't say. - We heard about that place...
- 他們沒有透露 - 聽說那地方的人
that they was all killed.
全都被殺光了
- That's why they didn't say. - Smokers?
- 那就是他們不透露的原因 - 掠海者干的?
Maybe Smokers, maybe Slavers.
也許是掠海者 也有可能是販奴商
So what's the word? We tradin' or not?
怎麼樣?要交易嗎?
We'll tally it like, uh, pure hydro.
我們就把它當成是 純淨水的價值交易
Works out to... 62 chits.
給你62塊錢
I want twice that.
我要加倍
- I just want one sip of hydro! - No, not 'til you tell me.
- 我只想喝一點水罷了 - 不行 除非你告訴我
She got inkings on her back. I seen her.
她背上有圖案 我看過
They say if you read the marks on the child,
傳說只要你能解開那孩子身上圖案之謎
they'll lead ya all the way to Dryland.
那就能指引你到達陸地
- Dryland's a myth. - Some still believe.
- 陸地只是神話 - 但還是有人相信
They say the Smokers even got an eye out for her.
他們還說掠海者在找這小女孩
Well, then, we'd better keep it to ourselves.
是嗎 那麼 我們最好還是保密
- Help you? - Yeah.
- 需要幫忙嗎 - 是的
- Where's the store? - You found it.
- 商店在哪? - 就你眼前
You don't have much.
東西不多
You the man with the dirt?
你就是帶著泥土的那個人?
Skoal.
乾杯
- One more. - Make it two.
- 再來一杯 - 來兩杯
A man this rich will buy for a fellow outwater, I'm sure.
一個這麼有錢的人會請陸上的朋友喝一杯的 我確定
One.
就一杯
That's an interesting pair of boots you got.
你腳上這雙鞋挺有趣的
- Trade? - No.
- 想交換嗎? - 不想
Shame.
真可惜
That's her
就是她
Enola. Hey, what are you doing?
埃諾拉 你在幹嘛?
No, you can't do that.
不行 你不能這樣
I need another piece.
我還需要一塊兒
I want to draw some more.
我想多畫點
I'll get it to you. Just stay in the back.
我會拿給你的 去後面呆著去
With all those chits, you could order up a bath.
用這筆錢 你能好好沖個澡
Have you ever had a freshwater bath?
你用淡水洗過澡嗎?
Why are you talkin' to me?
你為什麼找我說話?
Just being friendly.
我只想交個朋友
- Is that a tomato plant? - Yeah.
- 那是蕃茄樹嗎? - 對
You have a keen eye.
你很有眼光啊
Saw one in a picture. How much?
曾經在圖片上見過 怎麼賣的?
Half your chits.
你一半的錢
- I'll take them too. - Take what?
- 那些我也要 - 還要什麼?
- You bought everything. - I'll take them shelves.
- 東西全被你買了 - 那些架子我也要
So, what did you see out there in your 15 months?
你在海上那15個月堻ㄗㄗ儦L什麼
- Such as? - An end to all this water.
- 比如呢? - 這片水域的盡頭
Askin' the wrong person.
你問錯人了
The one they buried today?
他們今天不是埋葬了一個人嗎?
She found the only end there is.
她就是這兒的唯一盡頭
I've got a proposition for you, Mariner.
航海人 我給你一個建議
I'm not staying.
我不會留下來
We're not asking you to.
我們沒要你留下來
All we want is your seed.
我們要的是你的後裔
We can look to our own for impregnation,
找自己人雖然也行
but too much of that sort of thing gets... undesirable.
但是長此以往必會導致孩子的基因不良
When she's pregnant
只要她懷了孕
you go on your way with all the supplies you need.
你就可以帶上你所需的所有補給繼續你的行程
You don't have anything. You're dying.
別費神了 你們已經無藥可救了
No man stays out that long and turns down a woman.
沒有人會在漂泊那麼久之後竟對女人無動於衷的
- He's hiding something. - Maybe he's a Smoker spy.
- 他一定在隱瞞什麼 - 說不定他是個掠海者間諜
When the elders say so, you can leave,
只有長老讓你走 你才能走
and not before.
否則別想走
Gills.
有鰓
- Mutation! - He's a mutant!
- 變種人 - 他是變種人
My hand!
我的手
Throw the nets!
快撒網
By what right...
你憑什麼?
You pay me to keep the peace.
憑你雇我來維持這堛滲揮
This isn't it.
絕不是這樣的秩序
- He has killed one of ours. - He was defending himself.
- 他已經殺了我們一個人了 - 他只是自衛
He needs to be destroyed!
他必須被處決
Kill him. Let's kill him.
宰了他 我們得宰了他
That may be,
也許吧
but not here and not like this.
但絕不是在這兒更不是用這種方式
What is it?
那是什麼?
Damn.
該死的
It's tied. I can't get it off.
他們看得太緊了 我沒機會下手
Open the gate.
開門
Is it a map?
那是地圖嗎?
You'd tell me if you knew, wouldn't you, Enola?
如果你知道就告訴我 好嗎 埃諾拉?
- What are you drawing? - I don't know.
- 你在畫什麼? - 我不知道
Helen, look. Look at the prodigal child's latest vision.
海倫 你看 看這小天才的最新幻想
How soon before we can leave?
我們什麼時候才能走?
I don't have any idea yet where we can go.
我還不知道幾時能走?
I haven't figured out the tattoo on her back.
我搞不懂她的刺青
I'm a stupid man. The answer's right there.
我真是個蠢蛋 答案看似近在眼前
It's just beyond me.
實則遠在天邊
Maybe he knows.
也許他知道
Oh, yes, I see. They are webbed.
是的我看到了那是蹼
eight, nine, ten digits. That's wonderful.
8 9 有10個趾頭 真不可思議
They tell me, too, that you have gills.
他們說你有鰓
Isotropic gills. Are they merely vestigial or are they functional now?
排列整齊的鰓 是已經退化還是真的有用?
My name is Gregor. I've just come to pay you a little vi... vi...
我叫葛雷格 我是說過來給你點
Oh, my God.
老天啊
I'm sorry. I'm not laughing at you.
抱歉 我不是笑你
I'm excited. Your gills. They're functional.
只是有點興奮 你的鰓能用
Icthyus sapien. You can breathe in the water.
大自然的鬼斧神工啊 你能在水堜I吸
How deep can you go? Look, I'm only here...
你能潛多深?
Look, l'm only here because I want to learn more about you.
我來這兒只是想來好好瞭解下你
I can't say that I blame you. But tell me:
我也不怪你 告訴我
- I have no "kind." - Oh, fish rot.
- 我沒有同族 - 噢 那就是魚式退化
I'd be surprised if there weren't others, and if there aren't,
我好奇地是之前沒有 還是現在沒有呢
there will be eventually.
還是最終會有呢
Anyway, I've come here because I need to ask you a question.
唔 我來是因為有個問題要問你
Where... Where did your dirt come from?
你的泥土從哪兒來的?
Is it from Dryland?
從陸地來的嗎?
Do you know what this is?
你看得懂這個嗎?
The ancients... They did something terrible, didn't they?
古時候的人做了壞事 是不是
To cause all this water. Hundreds... Hundreds of years ago.
才導致了這個滿是水的世界 就在幾百 好幾百年前
If I tell you, will you open this lock?
如果我告訴了你 你肯開鎖嗎?
I haven't a key.
我沒鑰匙
- There's a mooring cleat down there. - What?
- 這下面有一個繫纜耳 - 什麼?
- Good as any key. - A mooring cleat?
- 那勝過任何鑰匙 - 繫纜耳?
I won't hurt anyone. I'll just leave.
我不會傷害任何人 我只想離開
What's your business there?
你在那媟F嘛?
- Move along! - I'm not a brave man.
- 快走吧 - 我不是個有膽識的人
If you know anything about Dryland, please tell me. Please!
如果你真知道陸地的事 請告訴我 求你了
Don't let it die with you.
別把它帶進墳墓
No, no, no, no. Stop!
不 別 別 別 停下來!
it is our decision that this mute-o...
我們決定這名變種人
does, indeed, constitute a threat.
的確對我們造成威脅
Therefore, in the interest of public safety,
因此為了公共安全
he is hereby sentenced to be recycled...
他被判處回收之刑
in the customary fashion.
遵照慣例執行
Proceed.
行刑
I'm sorry.
抱歉了
Bones to berries.
化骨為漿
Veins to vines.
抽脈為藤
His tendons to trees. His blood to brine.
肢骨化為大樹 血漿變鹽水
Too strange for life he was.
他的生命詭異而怪誕
This mute-o now does leave us,
變種人即將離我們而去
recycled and entombed, in the presence of him who leads us.
我們在神明面前收下他的恩澤並銘記他
Smokers! Dead out of the sun!
是掠海者 正從太陽的方向攻過來了
To your posts!
大家各就各位
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
老天啊 偶滴神啊
- Kill! - There!
- 大開殺戒 - 進攻
We are safe behind these walls.
在城牆內很安全
Aren't we?
是吧?
Let me out!
放我出來!
Let me out! I'll fight!
讓我也出來戰鬥
Give me the key to the city now.
傳令下去開始攻城
Let's go! Let's go! Let's go!
我們上 開攻了 開攻了
Floor it! Floor it! Floor it!
上膛 上膛 快
Swab it! Swab it!
快疏通 給我弄通
Goddamn! More ammo!
再裝子彈
Break down the door!
把門撞開來
My God!
老天爺啊!
We'll have this atoll in no time.
速戰速決拿下這座環礁基地
Crank it! Crank it!
轉起來!轉起來
Look!
注意!
Look out!
當心
Oh, no!
噢 不要啊
You get that goin'! Fill 'em up!
繼續充氣 讓它們鼓起來
Helen, come quickly!
海倫 快過來
Helen!
海倫
You're not supposed to go yet!
還沒到走的時候
Infernal machine!
可惡的東西
Gregor. Gregor, wait!
葛雷格 等等
Helen, I tried. There was an accident.
海倫 我試過了 出了點兒意外
I can't make it stop. Hurry!
停不下來了 動作得快點
You can make it if you try. Run! Up those stairs. Run! Quickly!
盡全力追上來 跑起來!快點!
- Wait! Wait! - I'll throw you a rope. Run quickly!
- 等等! - 我把繩子扔給你們 跑快點!
- Throw the rope now. Run, Enola. - Slow down! Wait!
- 把繩子丟下來 跑 埃諾拉 對不起
- Throw the rope. No! No! - Wait!
- 把繩子丟下來 不!不! - 等等!
- Gregor, don't leave us! - Oh, no!
- 葛雷格 別丟下我們! - 噢 不要
I'm sorry! It was an accident!
抱 這完全是個意外
Helen! Enola! Helen, I'm sorry!
海倫 埃諾拉 海倫 對不起
Shoot him. Shoot him.
射下他 把他射下來
If I let you out of here, you're taking us with you.
如果我救你出來了 那你就得帶上我們
Sure.
沒問題
Enola, get down.
埃諾拉 蹲下
Here. Get over here. Get down.
呆這兒 呆在這兒 蹲下來
Hurry! Come on!
快點 快
Get the gate.
去把大門打開
Run!
快點
Hurry up!
動作快點
Kamikazes. Come on!
自殺衝鋒隊 給我上
That made a hole.
炸了個大洞
Find her! Get the girl!
快找 抓住那個女孩
There!
在那邊
Go get that guy! Go! Kill him!
快 抓住那傢伙 快 滅了他
- Wow! - Enola!
- 哇! - 埃諾拉!
- You're too slow! - Run to the other side.
- 你們倆動作太慢啦 - 到另一邊去
Come on!
快點
Grab on! Hold on, hold on.
抓穩了 堅持住 堅持住
I'm stuck! I can't make it through!
勾住了 我過不去
Let her go!
放開她
Just drop her!
就讓她掉下來吧
Turn the wheel. The wheel! Turn it!
轉那個舵輪 舵輪 轉動它
That! Come on! Push it!
是那個 快呀 推動它
- I am! - Hurry! Now pull!
- 我在推呢 - 快!現在拉一下!
Push it! Push it hard! Push it hard!
推過去!用力推過去!推過去!
Okay, okay! Now pull this! Pull this!
好了 好了!現在拉這個!拉它!
Pull! Pull it! Hurry!
拉起來!快拉
Enola, jump.
埃諾拉 跳
- Look at me. Jump! Now! - Okay!
- 看著我 快跳 - 知道啦
Well, excuse me!
好了 打擾下!
Did I say anybody could leave before the battle was over?
我是不是說過攻擊結束前絕不能放任何人走?
- Did I? - No! No!
- 是不是? - 是的 是的
Well, do somethin'. I hate sails.
那就行動啊 我恨死了那些帆船
Hey! Can you steer?
嘿 你會操作嗎?
Can I trust you?
我能相信你嗎?
Answer me this, somebody. Why is that boat still firin'?
誰能告訴我 為什麼那艘船還在不停地開火
- What's that cousin's name? - Chuck.
- 那夥計叫啥名來著? - 查克
- Hey, Chuck! - He's pulling him right into us.
- 嘿 查克 - 他正把他的槍口拖向我們這邊
Maybe he doesn't answer to "Chuck."
也許他對查克這個叫法沒反應
Call him "Charles." Charles!
叫他查爾斯 查爾斯
Stop him! Stop him!
讓他停下來!叫他停下來
Charles!
查爾斯
Adios, cousins.
再見了 夥計們
She's here somewhere. Keep lookin'.
她一定在這兒 繼續找
Stop it!
停止!
What you got?
你搞什麼鬼啊?
Couple of heartbeats over there. Aren't sayin' much.
還留了幾個活口在那邊 但卻問不出什麼
If you'll notice the arterial nature of the blood
如果你們有注意到這鮮紅的血
comin' from the hole in my head,
都是從我頭上這個窟窿流出來的
you can assume that we're all havin' a real lousy day.
你們就應該想到我們今天真得過得很不爽
So here it is: I need to know about that tattooed girl.
所以現在 我要知道有紋身小女孩在哪兒
First one that tells me lives.
誰先說誰就能活命
I saw a girl. I saw, I saw...
我看到一個女孩 我看到
It was... Sh-She had a big tattoo on her.
是 她身上有一個很大的紋身
You won. Start over.
你贏了 重新來
I saw a girl. I'm not sure,
我看到一個女孩 雖然不是很肯定
but I think she got on that boat with three hulls.
但我想她上了那艘有三個船身的船
The boat that cost me a thousand G's of go-juice?
就是那艘浪費了我1000千克汽油的船嗎
Yeah, the mute-o's boat.
是的 那個變種人的船
- Mute-o? - Yeah. He got these slits here.
- 變種人? - 是的 他身上有一些裂縫
Like... Like fish gills.
就像是魚鰓一樣
He wasn't really a man.
他不算是地道的人類了
A fluke of evolution.
應該是一個偶然的進化
Oh, I'm sorry. A fluke of, uh...
噢 抱歉 一個偶然的
- Evolution. - I know!
- 進化 - 我知道
- No! No, you said you wouldn't kill me! - Did I say that?
- 不!不要 你說過不會殺我的 - 我說過那話?
- Witnesses, anybody, did I? - Yes, yes, yes! You said...
- 有誰聽到我說過嗎? - 是的 沒錯 你說過
- You said it. - Oh, I may have.
- 你確實說過 - 噢 我可能是說過
I may have.
可能是說過
tank up that sky boat; send it out on patrol.
給飛機加滿油 讓它出去巡邏
We gotta keep an eye out...
我們得睜大眼
for that ichthy-freak.
好好留意那個人魚怪物
You been there, haven't you?
你到過那兒 對吧?
Dryland?
陸地?
You know where it is.
你知道它的方位
Yeah, I know where it is.
對 我知道它的方位
And, uh... And we're going?
那麼 我們要去那兒嗎?
You and I are.
你和我可以
The kid we gotta pitch over the side.
那孩子我們得讓她下船
- What? - My boat's tore up.
- 什麼? - 我的船破了
I'm takin' on water.
我剛堵上了漏洞減少了進水
I'd be lucky to get half a hydro ration out of that.
幸好我還有那東西能過濾二次淡化水
You know... I said I won't drink.
你知道 我說了我不會喝的
For 12 days?
可以堅持整整12天?
No. It's better one of you dies now...
算了吧 最好犧牲你們其中一個
than both of you die slow.
免得你們死得很痛苦
Wait. Wait.
等一下 等等
We saved your life. We got you out.
我們救了你一命 幫助你逃出生天
No, you got me out so you could get out. We're even.
不 助我是為了幫你們自己罷了 我們算是扯平了
She can cook. She can fish.
她會煮飯 也會抓魚
- So can I. - Then take my necklace. Take my necklace.
- 我也會 - 那我的項鏈給你 拿著
- I got better ones below. - No, look!
- 我在下面能找到更好的 - 別 聽著
Oh.
哦
After what you went through back there on the atoll,
在環礁基地經歷的一切後
I can understand why you would want to.
我完全明白你想這麼做的原因
But she's a child.
但她還只是個孩子啊
Is there something else then?
那還有其他問題了嗎
Enola! Go below.
埃諾拉 到下面去
Enola.
埃諾拉
Yeah. You said so yourself.
是啊 你自己也說了
Been out there a long time.
出海漂泊很長時間了
Couple hours ago, I was potential dirt to you.
幾小時之前 我不過是你們眼中值得回收成泥土的傢伙
- We're not like that. - You all are.
- 我們並不像那些人 - 你們沒差別
Know what I was really thinkin'?
知道我當時真正的想法嗎?
Why I don't drop both of you in my wake right now.
為什麼我不趁自己清醒時把你們都扔下海呢
You got nothin' I need.
我對你沒任何興趣
You're taking us to Dryland.
你立馬帶我們到陸地去
Killing's a hard thing to do well.
殺人可沒那麼簡單
- Believe me. I'm not the one to start on. - Both of us!
- 相信我 要殺我就更不容易了 - 我們也是
How long you plan to hold that on me?
你打算用那玩意兒指著我多久?
As long as it takes.
需要多久就多久
- Okay. - No!
- 那好吧 - 不!
Let me out of here!
放我出去
Where the hell are you? Don't you touch my child.
該死的你在哪兒呢 別碰我的孩子
Come here!
過來啊
Okay, now don't move, okay? There.
好了 現在別動了 明白嗎?很好
Ohh. Oh, lookin' real good, yeah.
看起來真不錯 真的
There. There.
好了 好了
All done.
搞定了
Now, there may be some small problem in depth perception.
就現狀而言 在視覺的深度上可能會有一點小問題
Well, it better not screw up my short game.
是嗎 它最好別影響到我擊近球技術[高爾夫]
- Well? - Looks good. I like it. Yeah.
- 怎麼樣? - 很酷 我喜歡 是啊
- I like it better than your real eye. - Much better.
- 我覺得它比你的真眼還好看 - 好看多了
- What do you say, Toby? The truth. - Looks like shit.
- 你覺得呢 多碧? - 說實話像狗屎一樣
That's why I love children. No guile.
這就是我喜歡孩子的原因 不會說謊
It does look like shit.
真的像狗屎一樣
And it feels like cold shit!
感覺更像冰狗屎
Deacon? What...
帝剛?什麼事?
I'm sorry. L-lt's just that there's a problem in the pit.
抱歉 只是深井那邊出了點狀況
Maybe you should come.
可能需要您擺駕前去看看
Let's drive.
起駕
The pit. Don't bother with the scenic route.
到深井 別驚動了沿途的那些美景
Drive!
走啦!
Hey, it's drivin' better.
嘿 這開起來順手多了
Get off!
滾開點兒
Get over there. Get out of the way.
閃開 別占道
All right, all right, all right. Okay, okay.
好吧 行了 行了 好吧 好吧
You guys are great. Bless all you cousins over there.
祝福你們 兄弟們 祝福你們 祝福所有的兄弟們
Keep up the good work. Growth is progress. Growth is progress.
繼續努力 有成長就有進步 繼續努力 繼續努力
Somebody! Hey, up there!
有人嗎? 嘿 上面的
Take it off!
把井蓋打開
- Yes. - Your Deaconship.
- 什麼事? - 帝剛大人
Hello. Good morning. Or night,
你好 早上好 或者該晚上好
whichever the case may be.
管它的
- What is it? I'm a busy man. - I thought you should know.
- 有什麼事?我是大忙人 - 我想應該通知您了
We're down to exactly...
準確算來我們只剩下
four feet, nine inches of black stuff.
4尺9寸深的柏油了
Thank you, sir.
十分感謝 老大
How many G's is that after refinin'?
經過提煉之後能有多少千克?
Maybe three refuelers.
可能能灌滿三個加油器
- We'll burn through that in two lunars. - Sweet Joe!
- 夠我們用上兩個月 - 親愛的喬
Will somebody please tell me what's happened to this place?
誰能告訴我這個地方到底怎麼了
We outgrowed it.
供需太不平衡了
All right, the only thing that is important is the tattooed girl.
好了 現在最重要的就是那個有紋身的小姑娘
We don't spare any go-juice findin' her.
我們不可能為了省油而不去找她
We don't waste it anywhere else.
那麼在其他地方就別再浪費了
You cancel all those tractor pulls...
你們去關掉所有的牽引車
and all that stuff until later.
和其他耗油的東西
You got it?
聽懂了嗎?
Dryland is the mother lode.
陸地可是塊沃土啊
On your toes.
打起精神來
Excellent.
太好了
- Hi. - Move.
- 嗨 - 閃開
Enola! Enola, come here!
埃諾拉 埃諾拉 過來
Come on!
快點
Enola, come over here.
埃諾拉 到這邊來
Hey!
嘿
- What are ya doin'? - Decorating your boat. It's ugly.
- 你在幹嘛呢? - 給你船好好打扮一下 它太醜了
- Where did you get this? - From down below.
- 你在哪兒拿來的? - 下面拿來的
This is mine! You don't touch anything of mine.
這是我的 別碰我的東西
I drew it for you.
我是為你畫的
You don't draw on anything. You understand?
不需要你畫任何東西 聽明白了嗎?
What...
什麼?
This is my boat. I got it the way I like it.
這是我的船 就得按我的喜好來
You take up space and you slow me down.
你們佔了我的空間還拖慢了我的速度
You know, she's just a little girl.
她只是個小姑娘而言
- She doesn't know your rules. - You wanna stay?
- 還不懂你的規矩 - 想留在船上?
You teach her.
就好好教教她
Enola, what'd I tell you?
埃諾拉 我對你說過什麼來著?
You're not so tough. You know that?
你根本不是這麼鐵石心腸的 你自己清楚?
How many people have you killed?
你殺過多少人?
Ten? Twenty?
12?還是20個?
- You talk a lot. - I talk a lot 'cause you don't talk at all.
- 你很聒噪啊 - 我聒噪是因為你幾乎都一言不發的
Now how many?
多少個?
- Including little girls? - I'm not afraid of you.
- 包括小女孩嗎? - 我才不怕你
I told Helen you wouldn't be so ugly if you cut your hair.
我跟海倫說過如果你剪剪頭髮就不會這麼難看了
In fact, you talk all the time.
知道嗎 你老是說個不停
- It's like a storm when you're around. - Enola!
- 讓人就像陷入了風暴堣@樣 - 埃諾拉
Hey! What are you doing?
嘿 你在幹嘛?
- Helen! - You bastard! She can't swim!
- 海倫 - 你這渾球 她不會游泳
Help me! Helen!
救救我!海倫
Helen, help me!
海倫 救救我
Helen!
海倫
Helen! Helen!
海倫!海倫
Hold on!
堅持住
Look at me. Look at me. Look at me.
看著我 看著我 看著我
Oh, please, come back. Please!
求求你 回來 拜託了
Please! Oh, please!
拜託!噢 拜託了!
Hey!
嘿!
Hold on. Okay, almost...
堅持住 行了 沒事了
there.
那
Thanks. I swear,
謝謝 我發誓
if you ever touch her again...
如果你在碰她的話
You son of a bitch. Look at me.
渾球 轉過來
You will go to bed that night, and you will never wake up.
只要你會上床睡覺那你永遠也別想醒了
- Shut up. - What?
- 閉嘴 - 怎麼了?
- Smokers? - Yeah.
- 是掠海者嗎 - 對
Can't we outrun them?
我們能避開他們嗎?
Not with my sail down.
除非我沒收帆
- What are you thinkin' about? - That's a nice touch.
- 你犯什麼傻呢? - 多友好地揮手啊
That's them.
是他們
Don't hit the kid.
別傷了那孩子
Hey!
嘿!
Coward!
你個懦夫
Fuck!
可惡
No!
住手
Cut it!
切斷它
Come on! Come on!
加油 加油啊
All right. Okay.
好吧 好吧
Oh, I'm really sorry.
真的很抱歉
I'm sorry. But you didn't give me much choice.
真抱歉 你讓我別無選擇
Oh, I know.
我知道
But you ran away. L... What?
你開溜了 我 要幹嘛?
What are you do... No! Please, no! No!
你要幹嘛 別 求你了 不要啊
Don't ever touch anything on my boat again.
永遠別再碰我船上的任何東西了
She said she was sorry!
她已經向你道歉了
That means you're supposed to say something back!
意味著你應該有所回應才對
Did you say somethin'?
你在說話嗎?
The child... did he have the girl with him?
那個孩子 他帶著那個女孩嗎?
- Uh-huh. - Seems to me if we launch now,
- 對 - 如果我們馬上出發的話
we can cut him down just about here.
我們大概可以在這媞I住他
- If he doesn't change course. - Ah, it's not likely.
- 只要他不改變航道的話 - 那不可能
He's a wily one, that ichthy-demon.
他很狡猾的 那個臭魚人
Yeah, if he knows he's been spotted,
如果他知道自己已經被發現了
he'll expect us to expect him to change course,
他可能推測我們必定認為他改變了航向
which is exactly why he'll keep his heading.
所以他一定不會改變航向
The important question is, where's he heading?
重點是 他這是要去哪兒
And does he know how precious his cargo is?
以及他清楚自己船上的貨物價值嗎
I say that he's headed here, and we take him here.
他正向這兒趕 我們就在這兒攔截他
- Drifter? - Mm-hmm.
- 浪人? - 對
Are we gonna stop?
我們要停下來嗎?
- Look at the flag! - His flag's up.
- 看那旗子 - 他升起旗子
I thought you all stopped for each other.
我以為你們都互相幫助
Well... maybe he has some food!
也許他有食物
Don't find many who follow the rules anymore.
大家都不守規矩了
Well, make it quick. What's your business?
有話快說 你想幹嘛?
Trade.
交換東西
You got any resin?
你有樹脂嗎?
Resin? He's gotta be out of his mind. He's out of his mind. I don't have any resin.
樹脂?那是我的 全是我的
You been outwater a long time, haven't you?
你在海上很久了 對吧?
Must be jokin' me, man. Resin! You don't got enough.
是取笑我吧 哈 樹脂 你的東西可不夠換啊
How 'bout food?
有食物嗎?
Could you say that again, please?
能請你再說一次嗎
- How 'bout food? - Ah, yeah, food.
- 有食物嗎? - 啊 有 食物
Yeah, that'd be good, eh?
是啊 要有食物就好了
I haven't eaten in, well, you know, forever.
我都沒吃過 知道嗎 已經好長時間了
Which one of you two is a cook?
你們哪個是廚子?
'Cause I usually fall for the waitress.
因為我通常喜歡泡女服務生
Like you said, I don't have much.
像你說的 我沒多少東西
Now listen, eh? Let's see. What do I have to do?
聽著 讓我看看 那邊那些植物如何?
We can start with that wee orchard you got over there.
我們可以從你那邊那個迷你的小果園開始
All right, hold it there.
好了 呆在那兒別動
- We can talk. - Fair enough.
- 咱們談談 - 可以
It's a nice rod, isn't it?
真是漂亮的竹竿 不是嗎?
I like that rod. It's a nice rod.
我很喜歡 釣竿很棒
Got yourself a wee harem goin' here now, do ya?
你這兒可真是妻妾成群啊 不是嗎
What you want for the women?
這女人怎麼賣?
We're not for sale.
我們不是拿來賣的
Not for sale? There's no such thing as not for sale.
非賣品?根本不存在非賣品
"Not for sale"! Not for sale, eh?
非賣品 是非賣品嗎
- Are they a pair or would you consider sellin' 'em separate? - No.
- 成雙賣 還是分開賣 - 不
Our business is done here unless you got some resin for sale you can part with.
除非你能有樹脂或船帆可以交換
I told you once already, I don't have it.
我已經告訴你了 我沒有那些
I- I-I don't have it. Don't have it. Don't have it.
我沒有 沒有 沒有
Haven't seen neither for trade in lunars now. Wait. Wait, wait, wait.
已經好幾個月沒見到半個人來交意了 等等 先等等
I do have somethin' that'll make you change your mind.
我確實有些能讓你改變想法東西
Somethin' that you can't pass on.
讓你無法抗拒的東西
I took it off an Atoller refugee camp.
我從一個難民環礁基地弄來的
The life savings of the entire clan.
是整個氏族一輩子的積蓄
Paper.
紙張
It's paper. Have you ever seen paper? Look at it.
這可是紙啊 你見過紙嗎?你看看
Smell it.
聞聞看
I been savin' it for a special trade.
我一直珍藏著就是為了特別交易
Don't you do it.
別這麼做
You know, maybe I'm talkin' to the wrong person here.
我是不是找錯談判對象了啊
Whose boat is this? Is it your boat or your boat?
這艘船到底是誰的?究竟是你的船還是你的呢?
No. No, it's his boat. But he doesn't own us.
不 不 船是他的 但我們不是他的
Half an hour.
半小時
Out of his mind somethin' there.
他瘋啦還是怎麼了
I got two pages in here, man! I mean, I'd get half a dozen girls with this, you know.
我用這個至少能換個半打姑娘 你知道嗎?
Half an hour.
就半小時
- You tradin' or not? - Don't.
- 要不要隨你 - 別這樣
Shut up.
閉嘴
Okay.
好吧
Forty-five minutes with the wee one right there.
不然換45分鐘跟那邊那個幼齒吧
I like to do the talkin', if you know what I mean.
我更中意調教幼齒 你該明白的?
No!
不行
Fair. Come, come, come, come, come!
好吧 快過來 來 來 來 來啊
No. My boat.
不 就在我的船上
- Fair enough. Fair enough. Good, good, good. Aye. - Helen.
- 可以 可以 好的 好的 當然沒問題 - 海倫
- Sit down. - Enola, just do as he says.
- 坐下來 - 埃諾拉 乖乖聽他的話
It's been a while for me now.
這對現在的我而言只算得上一小會兒
Guess it's been more than a while, actually.
但事實上 那卻又不止一小會兒
I've only got half an hour.Half an hour, half an hour, half an hour...
我只有半個小時 半個小時 半個小時啊
Great, great, great...
對了 對了 很好
Ooh! You're so beautiful. Aye! Anyone ever told you that?
你好美 有人這麼稱讚過你嗎?
Give me that. What are you doin'? It's just a game.
少來這套 你這是在幹嘛?不就是睡一覺嘛
Oh, I, um... I, uh... We was just playin'.
我 我 我們剛剛只是想跟她玩玩
The trade's off.
不換了
I changed my mind.
我改變主意
Well, um... Well, you can't do that.
你不能反悔
I mean, a deal's a deal, eh?
都已經成交了啊
I just did.
我說了反悔了
Hey!
嘿
She's mine. Aye. No. No, no I own her. But... No.
她已經是我的了 不 不 我還沒碰到她呢 不行
- Go on. - Get, get, get. Go, go, go. Good, good.
- 走吧 - 行啊 行啊 走吧 走吧 很好 很好
But don't go too far now. This won't take but a minute.
別走得太遠 這耽擱不了一分鐘
I hate this boat. I hate this boat!
我恨這艘船 我恨透了這條船
You bastard.
你這渾球
You... You're pretty stingy for a man who's got everything, aren't ya now?
對於擁有這麼多東西的人來說你真是摳到家了
Where's me boat?
我的船在哪兒啊?
Help me to me boat.
帶我到船上
Ow! Me boat.
我的船
What the... No!
想幹嘛 別!
Never catch anything with this. It's useless.
用這個根本抓不到任何東西 就是個廢物
Look, I'm sorry. You were right about the pole.
聽著 我道歉 你說得很對 那竿子是廢物
You were right, but we have to eat.
你說得對是對 但我們還是得吃東西啊
Now I know you can hear me!
嘿 別裝聾作啞的
Now we can fish for ourselves. You show us what to do.
我們可以自己抓魚來吃 但至少你得告訴我們該怎麼做
You must know how. Even you gotta eat!
你要知道 即使是你也要吃東西的
You just sit there.
你們倆乖乖給我坐著
- What... - I don't know.
- 什麼玩意?... - 我不知道
Happy now?
滿足了?
You don't like my singing, do you?
你不喜歡我哼歌 對吧?
Helen says you don't like my singing 'cause you can't sing.
聽海倫說你之所以討厭我唱歌是因為你不能唱
- Ever try and listen? - To what?
- 你試著聆聽過嗎? - 聽什麼?
The sound of the world.
世界之音
- I don't hear anything. - That's because you're too loud,
- 我什麼也聽不到 - 那是因為你整天都吵個不停
and you're movin' around all the time.
你老是動個不停
Try sittin' still.
靜下來試試
Eyeball?
來顆魚眼?
I wish I had feet like his.
我也想要他那樣的腳
Then maybe I could swim.
也許我就能游泳了
Enola.
埃諾拉
Sorry.
抱歉
Never met a person couldn't swim before.
我之前還從來沒有見過不會游泳的人
I can't.
我就不會
People say I was weird.
別人都說我是個怪胎
Maybe they were right.
也許確如他們所說
Maybe they were right about you too.
也許你也確如他們所說
Enola wanted to give you this.
埃諾拉要把這個還給你
And this.
還有這個
She won't take it again.
她以後不會再拿了
You don't look much like her.
你跟她長得不太像
Well, I'm not her mother,
我不是她的生母
if that's what you're asking.
如果你想知道的是這個的話
You act like it.
你卻視她如親生一樣
What are those marks on her back?
她背上那些圖是什麼?
Nothing. They're just fanciful things.
沒什麼 只是好看而已
- Like what she draws? - She draws what she sees.
- 她畫的那些也是嗎? - 她只畫她見過得的東西
She's like a mirror.
她就如一面鏡子
People on the atoll thought she was a...
大家一度認為都認為她是…
Freak?
怪胎?
Uh-huh. Yeah.
對
I just thought she was special.
我卻認為她很特別
I'm not givin' it to her. It's just...
我並不是要給她 只是...
A loan.
借她用
Yeah. I'm not givin' it to her.
對 我不是給她
Is Dryland beautiful?
陸地很美嗎?
You'll see.
你會親眼所見的
Enola?
埃諾拉
Enola, what are you doing?
埃諾拉 你在幹嘛?
- Those monsters'll kill her! - No, they're asleep now.
- 那些怪物會殺了她的 - 它們都在睡覺
Hands around my neck.
抱住我的脖子
Let the water tell your arms and legs how to move.
讓你的手和腳在水的帶領下動起來
We're goin' down. Hold your breath.
我們要潛下去 憋住呼吸
- What is it? - What is it?
- 怎麼了? - 那是什麼?
Barter outpost.
易物交易的前哨站
You said we'd get to Dryland today.
你說我們今天會到達陸地的
Today. Tomorrow. What's it matter?
今天 明天 都無所謂
I need resin.
我需要樹脂
- What is that? - It's PortuGreek. Their own language.
- 那是什麼話? - 是葡希文 他們自己的語言
Or so I thought.
不然就是如我所料
Ah.
呃
- There's my girl. - Yeah.
- 那就是我要的小姑娘 - 是啊
Howdy, darlin'. Come on in here now.
您好啊 小可愛 快到我們懷抱堥荍a
- What's going on? - Smokers.
- 怎麼回事? - 是掠海者
What the hell?
搞什麼鬼?
He's spotted us. Sound it!
穿幫了快發信號
Sound it! Sound it! Sound it! Sound it!
發信號快發信號快發信號
Yahoo!
噢哦
Enola!
埃諾拉
Starboard side! Now!
到右舷去馬上
Get in the chair!
站到椅子上
Watch it. He's clearin' the net.
注意他入網了
Go to the helm.
你去掌舵
- Get the centerboard! - Centerboard?
- 把舯板打開 - 舯板?
What centerboard? I don't know what to do!
- 舯板是啥? - 到底是要我做什麼?
It's too late. Over here!
太遲了 快過來
No!
不是吧
Gimme that rifle. Boy, if you wanna do somethin' right,
來福槍拿來 想做好一件事
you've got to do it yourself.
自己動手才能豐衣足食
All right.
好的
- I winged him. - I say we load...
- 我打到他了 - 我說我們...
all the go-juice onto one boat and run the freak down.
快點派一艘船去逮那怪物
You can't catch him in ten boats, and you wanna send just one?
你派了十艘都沒能抓住他 你還想一艘就能得逞
Well, I pray that you're jokin'.
你是在講冷笑話吧
Bring me the trackers.
把追蹤器給我拿來
He's hurt.
他受傷了
It's not what you think. They weren't after her.
他們不是來抓她
- I saw what I saw. - What?
- 我是親眼所見 - 什麼意思?
No more lies.
別再跟我撒謊了
What are the marks on her back?
她背上的究竟是什麼
People say it's the way to Dryland.
大家都說那是通往陸地的指示
Dryland's a myth!
陸地只是個神話
No! You said so yourself that you know where it is.
不可能 你自己說過你知道它在哪兒的
You did.
你說過
You're a fool to believe in something you've never seen before.
你居然蠢得去相信見都沒見過的東西
I've seen it. I've touched it!
我不光見過 我更摸過
Dirt that was richer and darker than yours.
那泥土比你帶來的更肥沃 色澤更深
It was in the basket we found Enola in!
就在發現埃諾拉的那個籃子
- It doesn't exist! - Well, how can you be so sure?
- 那根本就不存在 - 你憑什麼那麼肯定?
Because I've sailed farther than most have dreamed, and I've never seen it.
因為我的航程早已遠過了那些夢想之地 而我卻從未見到過
But the things on your boat!
但你船上的那些東西呢
"Things on my boat" what?
我船上的東西 指什麼?
There are things on your boat that nobody has ever seen!
你船上那些個沒人見過的東西
What are these shells?
像這些貝殼吶?
And that reflecting glass?
還有那個反光鏡啊
And th-the music box? That...
以及那個音樂盒 那個
Well, if not from Dryland, then where? Wh-Where?
那不是陸地來的 那是哪兒來的呢?哪兒來的?
You wanna see Dryland?
你想看陸地嗎?
You really wanna see it?
你真的那麼想看嗎?
I'll take you to Dryland.
我就帶你到陸地
Get in.
下水
- Well, what about Enola? - There's only air for one.
- 埃諾拉怎麼辦? - 這兒的空氣只夠一個人用
- Get in the water. - It'll be all right.
- 快下來 - 沒事的
Don't touch anything.
別亂來啊?
Okay?
好了嗎?
I didn't know.
真沒想到
All this time...
這麼久以來
Nobody does.
沒有人知道
Can you get us outta here?
我們逃得掉嗎?
I'd say there're two chances o' that.
要我說倒是兩種可能性
- Hey! - No way and no how.
- 嘿! - 那就是無處可逃 無計可施
Shoulda bought me that drink. Come on!
早就叫你請我喝一杯的 上來
This way. Come on!
上來 快
Proper introductions first.
首先正式地自我介紹一下
I'm the Deacon.
我就是帝剛
If you don't recall the face, perhaps it's
如果不記得我這張臉了 可能是
'cause I didn't always look like this.
因為之前我的臉可並不是這個樣子
Now, ahem, I suspect she's somewhere real close.
我一直在猜她到底躲在哪
So we can tear this boat apart lookin' for her,
為了找到她 我們不得不痛心地拆了這艘船
but I'd rather somebody tell me where she is.
但是我更希望有人能告訴我她躲在哪兒
And the first one that does that, lives.
誰先說誰就能活下來
And the runner-up... Well, actually, there are no runners-up.
而亞軍就 事實上 壓根就不會有亞軍
Oh, sweet Joe, I love this part.
哦 親愛的喬 這可是我的最愛
Choose 'em. One, two. Live or die.
自己挑吧 第一名還是第二 生還是死
You know, personally,
就我個人而言
I'd rather shoot the sperm-of-the-devil here.
我更喜歡留下你來好好享用
Huh? But you know somethin'?
但就算你知道
I don't think you're gonna tell me, are ya?
我想你也不會告訴我的 對嗎?
Huh? Too bad.
真遺憾
Come on, eh? What do you say?
好了 有什麼要說的嗎
She's not your kind.
她又不是你同類
You don't even have a kind.
你根本就沒有同類吧
If you say it, he'll still kill us both.
你告訴了他 他還是會殺了我們倆
Let's not get ahead of ourselves.
咱就別相互為難彼此了
If you don't tell me,
如果你不說
I swear to Poseidon I will torch your boat.
我以波塞冬海神之名起誓我一定燒了你的船
Refresh my memory. What happens when neither of 'em talks?
提醒我一下 之前遇到這種情況時是怎麼做的來著?
- Never happened before. - Never happened before.
- 從沒遇到過 - 從沒遇到過
All right!
好啊
If they won't tell us where she is, do 'em! Both of 'em! Kill 'em now!
如果他們不說 就幹掉他們
- No! - No!
- 不要 - 不要
So gullible! Bring her here.
真好騙 把她帶過來
Take and ye shall receive! - No! Leave her!
- 到手了 - 不 放開她!
So ends your daily sermonette!
今天的布道就到此結束啦
All we gotta do is figure out this map. Turn her upside down.
我們只要能搞懂這個地圖就成了 把她倒過來衣服揭開
- Does that mean anything to you? - No.
- 你看得明白嗎? - 不明白
We'll figure it out back at the 'Deez. Back at the 'Deez, boys.
回帝斯號去慢慢琢磨 兄弟們 打道回府了
Careful with her. Careful with her!
好好看著她 小心點
- What about them? - Do 'em both.
- 他們呢? - 兩個都幹掉
Torch the boat.
船也燒了
We have to go under!
我們得潛下水
No, I can't breath like you!
不行 我不像你能在水下呼吸
I'll breathe for both of us.
我可以讓我們倆同時呼吸
Helen!
海倫
Helen, help! Helen! Helen!
海倫 救救我!海倫 海倫
My boat.
我的船
Enola.
埃諾拉
What is this? Get those chains off her.
這算什麼?把她的鐐銬解開
What are we, barbarians here?
怎麼?我們是野蠻人嗎?
Goodness gracious. Sakes alive.
我的老天啊 太沒人性了
Come on. Outta here, you big, nasty animal, you!
快滾 滾出去 你這個又肥又討厭的東西
You wanna come over here and sit on my lap?
要過來坐我的大腿上嗎?
No? Ahem.
不要?
How 'bout a cigarette?
來根香煙如何?
Nothin' like a good smoke if you miss your mom.
抽根香煙快樂似神僊
Never too young to start.
多小開始抽都沒關係
No. Well, I got somethin' right here I know you'd like.
不要 好吧 有些東西我知道你一定喜歡
Like to draw, don't you? Huh?
你很喜歡畫畫 對吧?
Huh? Now they're yours...
他們都可以給你
if you help me with just one problem, all right?
只要你幫我一個忙 行嗎?
Now, ahem... Now that tattoo on your back... Ahem.
你背上的那個紋身
I've been told that, uh... that's actually a map?
我聽說那似乎是一份地圖是嗎 聽說那其實是地圖
It's the way to Dryland.
那是通向陸地的指示
Now we're gettin' someplace.
看來我們找到地方了
Could you teach me how to read that?
你能教我怎麼看嗎?
Setback.
功虧一簣啊
Well, have you ever heard any of your friends talk about it?
那你曾聽你的哪位朋友討論過那個紋身嗎
You know, like your mommy or your pet fish? Did he say anything?
比如你媽媽或者是你的寵物魚叔叔 他說過什麼嗎?
You shouldn't make fun of him. He wouldn't like it.
你不該嘲笑他的 他會不高興的
Girl, I don't give a shit what he'd like. He took out my eye.
我才不管他喜不喜歡 他弄瞎了我的一隻眼
And if I ever see him again, I'm gonna cut open his head and eat his brains!
如果再讓我看到他 我一定要開他的腦吸乾他的腦髓
You think he'd like that?
他會喜歡那樣嗎
Can't kill him. He's even meaner than you are.
根本殺不了他他可比你狠多了
But he's not here.
但他不在這兒
And he ain't comin'.
更不會來這兒
And no one's gonna save you.
所以根本沒人會來救你
He'll come for me. He will.
他一定會來救我的 一定會
Then you better tell me what I wanna know
那你最好乖乖地從實招來
or he can see what's left of you in a goddamn jar.
否則他能救到的只會是個屍骨無存的你
We're going to die here, aren't we?
我們死定了 對不對?
Aren't we?
是嗎?
After the atoll,
逃出環礁基地後
when I offered myself to you,
我曾要獻身給你
why didn't you take me?
你當時為什麼會拒絕呢?
'Cause you didn't really want me.
因為你並不是真得想要我
Not really.
你不是自願的
Have I been asleep long?
我睡了很久嗎?
I was dreaming.
我做了個夢
It's funny.
很奇怪
I always thought Dryland floated.
我一直以為陸地是漂浮著的
That it drifted with the wind.
它會隨風而動 所以才那麼難找
That's why it was so hard to find.
為什麼你會如此地深信不疑
Why did you believe in it so much?
你為什麼深信有陸地?
Because we weren't made for the sea.
因為我們根本無法在海洋中生存
Got hands... and feet.
看看我們的手和腳
We're supposed to walk.
那是用來行走的
I miss her sound.
我好想念她的聲音
Don't you?
你呢?
Helen!
海倫
He... No, no, no. Helen, up here. Above you!
不 不對 不對 海倫 抬頭 你頭上
Gregor!
葛雷格
Smart thinking to burn your boat.
很機靈啊 燒了你們的船
Without the smoke, I never would have found you.
要不是看到了濃煙 我永遠都無法找到你們
Who's that with you?
和你一起的那傢伙是誰
Ichthyus Sapien, is that really you?
那個魚神?真的是你嗎?
I'll throw the rope down. You catch it. I'll help you climb up.
我把繩子扔給你們 抓牢了 我把你們拉上來
Helen. Where's Enola?
海倫 埃諾拉呢?
Smokers took her. They'd have me too if it weren't for him.
被掠海者抓走了 幸好有他在 我才倖免於難
My friend, thank you. Very human of you.
我的朋友 謝謝你 你非常地有人性
Go grab your things quickly. Quickly. Come.
快把你們的東西拿上 動作快 快
You see? Right down there.
看到了嗎?就在這下面
There's several of us survivors. We'll just start over again.
那是基地的一些倖存者 我們正準備重新開始
You can't ask us to go get her!
你不能要求我們都去救她
Enola's the reason we're in all this trouble.
埃諾拉正是這場劫難的根源
They don't have any reason to kill her. They need to find Dryland just like we do.
反正他們又不會殺了她 他們跟我們一樣在找陸地
- Of course. - If the Mariner's willing to go, why not us?
- 毫無疑問 - 連那個浪行者都願意去了 我們怎麼能無動於衷呢
If he wants to go, then let him!
他願意就讓他去呀
We don't want you here! You or the girl!
我們根本不想收留你們 你和那個女孩都是
Helen. The papers the Mariner brought you...
海倫 那個航海人給你的這些紙紙
It's the same language the tattoo is written in. They're numbers.
上面的文字和紋身上面的文字是同一種語言 上面有號碼
- Gregor, you're as crazy as she is! - We can't stay here!
- 葛雷格 你和她一樣瘋狂 - 我們不能呆在這兒
We're wasting valuable time.
我們再不抓緊時間
More Smokers will come.
更多的掠海者就會追來了
We need to be moving now!
我們需要馬上轉移
My friends, don't you see we need this child if we want to find Dryland?
我的朋友們 你們還不明白嗎 想要找到陸地我們就需要那個孩子
- I'm not goin'. - Nobody is.
- 我才不會去呢 - 誰都不去
We've seen their smoke on the horizon!
我們遠遠就看到他們的煙
- Know what that is yet? - The numbers? Yes, I think I do.
- 搞懂那個是什麼了嗎? - 這些數字嗎?當然 我想我搞懂了
It seems to be some ancient form of geographic location: Latitude, longitude.
這看起來應該是過去的地理坐標 是緯度和經度
It doesn't make sense, though. The numbers, they seem to be backwards or something.
不過 有點不合理 這些數字 似乎是顛倒的還是怎麼了
- It's upside down. - The world?
- 確實是顛倒的 - 整個世界嗎?
The poles have reversed themselves?
兩級也是顛倒的?
I've been mappin' the cities below.
我一直在勘測水下的城市
The world wasn't created in a deluge. It was covered by it.
世界並不是在水中建起的 而是被水淹沒了
- That's blasphemy! - No, it's true.
- 那話簡直是褻瀆神靈 - 不 那是事實
I've seen it with my own eyes. There is land. It's right under our keel.
我親眼所見那些土地就在我們身下這片海底
- None of it's dry anymore. - Some is.
- 根本就沒有干地 - 有些是
Enola's been there. I know that now. I saw what she drew.
埃諾拉確實曾到過那兒 在看到她畫得那些畫之後 我很肯定
So that's why he's going after Enola... to find Dryland.
所以你是為了陸地找她
I don't care about Dryland.
我才不管陸地
This is ridiculous. Going after the Smokers?
真是太荒謬可笑了 要怎麼找掠海者啊
He doesn't even know which direction they came from.
他連他們打哪兒來的都不知道
- I say let him go. - We're better off without them anyway!
- 我說讓他走吧 - 沒有他更好
If she's alive, I'll bring her back to you.
只要她還活著 我就一定把她帶回來
Forget the mute-o, Helen. If he brings her back, they'll kill us!
得了 別管那個變種人了 海倫別 如果他帶她回來我們都會死
I can't stand it. We gotta go help him. I can't ask him to do this alone.
我不能袖手旁觀 我們得去幫幫他 不能讓他一個人冒險
Oh, don't worry, my dear. You're not going to have to.
噢 放心吧 親愛的 你想去的話簡單得多
You got that tattoo figured out yet?
你們搞懂紋身的涵義了嗎?
It would be easier if it was flat... big and flat.
如果再平整點就容易多了 最好又大又平整
- It needs to be flat. - What you got in mind?
- 這得攤平了來看 - 你到底想幹嘛?
Well, you cut it off her back. You stretch it, mount it.
最好能從她背上割下來 就可以攤平了 甚至裱起來
- Give us a proper look. - Take her down below until I holler.
- 我們就能慢慢研究了 - 把她帶下去等我叫她
Saint Joe, we're close.
偉大的喬 就要到頭了
After centuries of shame.
在經歷了幾世紀的屈辱之後
- They're gettin' ugly. - Don't I know it.
- 他們開始有點暴躁了 - 聽出來了
Announce me, cousin.
可以開始了 兄弟
Hey. Here he is.
注意了 他來了
Deacon!
帝剛
Rise up, brothers and sisters.
熱情點 兄弟姐妹們起來
Turn your eyes and open your hearts...
睜開你們的雙眼打開胸襟
to your humble benefactor,
你們仁慈的佈施者
your spiritual shepherd and dictator for life,
你們靈魂的引導者 命運的依托者
the Deacon of the 'Deez.
帝斯號的帝剛
- Look out! - It's mine! It's mine!
- 當心! - 是我的!是我的!
- Deacon! - Wahoo!
- 帝剛 - 哇
Children. Children of the provider.
孩子們 我可愛的孩子們
Citizens of the good ship. Please now, hear me speak.
帝斯號的好船民 安靜下來聽我說
- I've had a vision. - Yeah, we're tired of your visions!
- 我見到了一個幻象 - 我們已經受夠了你的那些幻象了
What about the land you promised us?
你對我們許諾過的土地在哪兒呢
Yeah! Yeah!
是啊!是啊
Oh ye of little faith.
你們對信仰太不堅定了
I've had a vision so great...
我看到的這個幻象如此美好
that as it came to me, I wept.
美好到讓我感激涕零
- And in this splenditudinous figment of wonder, - Is that Bone's ride?
- 讓我以為那只是南柯一夢 - 這不是波恩的摩托艇嗎?
- Is that blood on the seat? - I saw...
- 座位上是血跡嗎 - 我見到的
And you know what it is that I saw.
你知不知道我看到了什麼
I saw... the land.
我看到...陸地
Horse, that you?
霍斯 是你嗎?
Look, just bring it in slow, okay? I don't have all day.
慢慢的開進來 別浪費時間
Horse!
霍斯
Just bring it up slow.
慢慢開進來
I said slow!
慢慢開進來!
Shouldn't be doing that. You're gonna get in trouble.
你不應該這樣 你會惹麻煩
Ha. That's right.
是啊 是啊
You're not afraid. You've got your pet freak comin' to rescue you.
而你沒有害怕 因為你在期盼著你那可愛的怪物叔叔來救你
He's not a freak, and he can take you anytime.
他才不是怪物呢 他隨時都能要了你的命
He's killed dozens of people, and he doesn't have any mercy or anything.
他殺人無數 冷血無情 更不會心慈手軟
He even kills little girls.
他連小女孩都殺
Haven't we all?
難道我們就會嗎
Shit.
該死的
It's Horse.
是霍斯
- Find him. Find him! - Come on!
- 去找他 去找他 - 快
Yes! Yes! Yes!
是的!是的!是的!
- Come on. - Gettin' nervous, aren't you?
- 快來 - 有點緊張了 是嗎?
I don't get nervous.
我不會緊張
And if there's a river, we'll dam it.
如果有河 我們就建壩蓄水
And if there's a tree, we'll ram it.
如果有樹 我們就大興土木
'Cause I'm talkin' progress here.
因為此刻我說的可是發展
Yes, sir. I'm talkin' development.
是的 我說的是開拓
- Yeah! - For we shall suck and savor...
- 是的 - 因為我們馬上就能盡情地舔吸
the sweet flavor of Dryland.
陸地的沁人芬芳
Face is all red.
你的臉已經都紅了
Helen said with anybody that has a face that red,
海倫說過如果有人的臉紅得已經成了關公那樣
he's had too much sun or too much to drink.
那他不是曬得太久就是喝多了
All right, that's it. I'm gonna burn your face.
行了 我受夠了 看我不毀了你的小臉蛋兒
Almost time.
時間剛剛好
- What's up? - We're just talkin' about our friend.
- 怎麼了? - 只不過是剛剛聊起了她朋友
- What's his name? - He doesn't have a name.
- 他叫什麼名字? - 她沒有名字
So death can't find him.
所以死神無法找到他
Doesn't have a home or people to care for.
他無親無故 沒有任何後顧之憂
He's not afraid of anything, men least of all.
他渾身是膽 無所畏懼
He's fast and strong like a big wind.
他就像颶風一樣強大而迅猛
He can hear a hundred miles and see a hundred miles underwater.
在水下他更是來去自如
He can hide in the shadow of the noon sun.
他能躲在太陽陰影下
He could be right behind you, and you won't even know it 'til you're dead!
他可以潛伏在你身後 你死了都不知道
Give it a rest.
讓你的嘴歇歇
He'll come for me. He will.
他會來救我的 一定會
- We are the people... - Yeah?
- 我們就是開拓先鋒 - 是嗎?
- Well, I hope he does. - The Lord's creation.
- 希望如此 - 這是神的恩澤
Remember you said that.
記住你說過這句話
Look at us.
瞧瞧我們
- Look at us here today. - Yeah!
- 好好看看今天還在這堛漣畯 - 是的
Dryland is not just our destination,
陸地不僅僅是我們的夢之地
but it is our destiny!
也是我們的命運
Find him. Find him!
快去找他 把她找出來!
How can I find...
我該怎麼找到
this glorious place?
這片樂土
And he said to me:
他對我說
"A child shall lead you."
你將遇見一個孩子
A child.
一個孩子
- And behold! - It's time.
- 看哪 - 是時候了
The instrument of our salvation!
我們的救星
Our guide in the wild.
我們迷途上的嚮導
Our beacon in the darkness.
黑暗堛獄滽餈O
Turn her around, Nord.
把她的背轉過來 諾德
She has shown me the path!
她已經給我展示了路徑
And before the holy-most moment is upon us,
在最神聖的時刻來臨之際
let's sacrifice one to old Saint Joe.
讓我們為了偉大的老喬徹底瘋狂一把
And let's get this tub of shit up to speed.
把我們這蛈p廢鐵的破船開動起來 全速前進
Pull!
快劃
- Pull! - Pull!
- 快劃 - 快劃
- So which way we rowin'? - I don't have a goddamn clue.
- 我們要往哪個方向劃? - 我他媽的也毫無頭緒
Don't worry.
別緊張
They'll row for a month before they figure out I'm fakin' it.
等他們察覺被騙時起碼也過了一個月了
But, um, wh-wh...
但是為什麼呢
Oh, you want details. Well, I'm not tellin' these savages...
你想知道實情 不能告訴這些人
that we haven't solved the map yet.
我們還沒搞懂地圖
I promised them results, and I'll get 'em if I gotta cut 'em out of her goddamn back.
我向他們保證有結果 我會不擇手段得到結果的
Who is that? Who is that?
那是誰?那是誰?
Maybe one of the spare rowers?
也許是個划槳的後備吧?
Why aren't you rowin'?
你怎麼不去划槳呢?
- It's him. - It is him.
- 是他 - 確實是他
You guys are in so much trouble.
你們麻煩可大了
Well, I'll be damned. It's the gentleman guppy.
真的想不到 是那個魚人
You know, he's like a turd that won't flush.
他好像洗不掉的狗屎
I want the girl.
把那小姑娘給我
You know, I thought you were stupid, friend.
知道嗎?我以為你只是很蠢 老兄
But I underestimated you.
不過我確實太低估你了
You're a total freakin' retard.
你簡直就是個低能兒
I want the girl. That's all.
我只要那個女孩兒
Well, what on this screwed-up Earth makes you think you're gonna get her?
哦 在這荒涼殘敗的地球上 你憑什麼認為你辦得到?
You know what this is?
你知道這是什麼嗎?
I drop it, you burn.
我丟下去你就毀了
- We all burn. - Now wait, wait, wait, wait.
- 大家都會毀了 - 等等 等等 先等等
Ahem. Let's not do anything rash here.
都別衝動
I mean, uh, are you sure she's worth all this?
你確定她真的值得你這麼做嗎?
She never does stop talkin'. She never shuts up.
她總是嘮叨個沒完沒了 從不閉嘴
- I noticed. - What is it then?
- 我清楚得很 - 那你是為什麼?
Huh? It's the map.
是為了地圖?
She's my friend.
她是我的朋友
Golly gee. A single tear rolls down my cheek.
我真是感動得熱淚直流
I mean, you're gonna die for your friend.
你居然要為了你的朋友準備慷慨就義
If it comes to that.
如果真有必要的話
He's bluffing. I'll kill him.
只不是虛張聲勢罷了 我要殺了他
He's not bluffing. He never bluffs.
他不是虛張聲勢 他從不會那麼做
Shut up!
給我閉嘴
I don't... l-l... I don't think you're gonna drop that torch, my friend.
我打賭你絕不會扔的 我的朋友
- Why not? - Because you're not crazy.
- 為什麼? - 因為你又不是瘋子
No!
不
Oh, thank God.
哦 真是感謝上帝
Look out!
當心
Get him!
逮住他
Let's go, goddamn it!
快點 可惡
Don't just stand there! Kill somethin'!
別淨站著 給我上
Was this your big vision?
這就是你偉大的幻景嗎?
Oh, yeah! I've always wanted to drive this monster.
我一直渴望能開開這玩意兒
There he is! There he is!
是他 在那
That's him! There!
在那
No! Let go!
不 放手
Let go!
放手
- Let me go! Let go! - Pilot!
- 放手 放手 - 飛行員
- Pilot! - Let me go!
- 飛行員 - 放了我
Let go!
放了我!
You should've stayed underwater.
你乖乖呆在水下就沒事了
Now you know how to fly an airplane? You're lucky I do.
你知道怎麼駕駛飛機嗎?幸好我懂 真慶幸對吧
Ow! Now you stop it! You behave yourself now!
別這樣 給我聽話點兒
It's going down.
它正在下沉
- You can see it sinking. - Gregor, bring us right down on top of it.
- 你能看見它在下沉 - 葛雷格 降到那艘船上方
- Hurry, Gregor! - Don't worry.
- 快點 葛雷格 - 別擔心
Hurry.
快點
Enola! Up here!
埃諾拉 快上來
Grab on!
抓住繩子
Are they on yet?
他們倆都抓住了嗎
- What is it? - I don't know!
- 怎麼回事兒? - 不知道
No!
不
Gotcha! I'm gonna rip your cute little lungs out.
抓到你了 我要好好地收拾你一頓
Pull! Almost.
用力 差不多了
No!
不
No! Enola!
不 埃諾拉
Saint Joe. Hole in one.
偉大的喬啊 這一桿進洞真漂亮啊
- Helen! - No! Enola! - Helen!
- 海倫 - 不 埃諾拉 - 海倫
Hey! Hey!
嘿!嘿
Ohh. Oh, no! Quick! What are we gonna do?
哦 不 快想辦法啊 該怎麼辦
Tie this off.
把這頭綁緊
- Hurry! - Tie it!
- 快點 - 綁緊這頭
- Got it! - Ah!
- 好了 - 噢
Get 'em up now.
快拉他們上來
- Of course! North is south. - What?
- 當然 北是南 - 什麼
- South is north. - I was swimming.
- 南是北 - 我會游泳了
- I saw. - My friends.
- 我看到了 - 我的朋友們
My friends, look.
朋友們 快來看看
If I take a bearing from the sun
只要我測出來太陽高度角
and reverse the coordinates on Enola's back,
再顛倒一下埃諾拉背上的那些數據
then Dryland is that way!
那麼 陸地就應該是在那個方向
It's fresh!
是淡水
All of this! It's fresh!
是淡水 全是淡水
No!
不!
Whoo! Whoo!
哇哦
I found something!
我發現了點東西
Maybe we should put them under the dirt.
也許我們應該讓他們入土為安
I think it was their way.
我想那是他們的風俗
They must have known they were dying.
他們一定早就知道自己將不久於人世了
I'm home.
我到家了
- Where's the Mariner? - He was outside.
- 航海人在哪? - 在外面
Wait. Wait! I want to show you this.
等等 先等等!我想讓你看看這個
First time in your life you got nothin' to say?
這可能是你有生以來第一次隻字不說吧?
Enola, I have to go now.
埃諾拉 我不得不馬上離開
But you came back for me.
但你曾為了我去而復返
I like you.
我喜歡你
Why are you leaving?
你為什麼要走?
- I don't belong here. I belong out there. - You belong here.
- 我不屬於這 我屬於外面的世界 - 你屬於這
It's too strange here. It doesn't move right.
呆在這兒讓我覺得很彆扭 因為一切都是靜止的
Helen said that it's only land sickness.
海倫說那只不過是還沒有適應腳踏實地的感覺罷了
We're all feeling it. It'll go away soon.
我們都有這種感覺 但很快就能適應了
It's more than that.
不只是如此